Death comes for all men.
Bone Tomahawk is a western, horror, drama film directed by S. Craig Zahler.
During a shootout in a saloon, Sheriff Hunt injures a suspicious stranger.
The doctor's assistant, wife of the local foreman, tends to him in prison.
That night, the town is attacked and they both
disappear—only the arrow of a cannibal tribe is found.
Hunt and a few of his men go in search of the prisoner and the foreman's wife.
Sheriff Franklin Hunt, played by Kurt Russell.
Arthur O'Dwyer, played by Patrick Wilson.
Chicory, played by Richard Jenkins.
John Brooder, played by Matthew Fox.
Samantha O'Dwyer, played by Lili Simmons.
Purvis, played by David Arquette.
Bone Tomahawk is a 2015 American Western film written and directed by S.
Craig Zahler in his directorial debut, and starring Kurt Russell, Patrick Wilson, Matthew Fox, Richard
Jenkins, Lili Simmons, Evan Jonigkeit, David Arquette, Zahn McClarnon and Sid Haig.
It was produced by Jack Heller and Dallas Sonnier.
The film is about a small-town sheriff who leads a posse into a desolate region to rescue
three people who were abducted by a cannibalistic clan of troglodytes.
Development of the film started when Zahler's friend and manager Sonnier recommended
creating a film adaptation of Zahler's Western novel Wraiths of the Broken Land.
Realizing that such a project could not be adapted on a low
budget, Zahler opted to write a rescue Western instead.
Casting began in October 2014, with Peter Sarsgaard, Timothy Olyphant, and Jennifer Carpenter signed on to
play before being replaced by Wilson, Fox, and Simmons respectively due to scheduling conflicts.
Principal photography took place in California over a
course of 21 days in October 2014.
The premiere of Bone Tomahawk took place at Fantastic Fest on October 1, 2015.
RLJ Entertainment gave the film a limited release on October 23, grossing over $480,000 in
theater sales and $4.32 million in home media sales against a $1.8 million budget.
The film received mainly positive reviews, with praise for Zahler's
screenplay and direction and the performances of the ensemble cast.
It has now become a modern cult classic.
The film explores themes of rescue, sheriff, prisoner, ambush, poison.
The tone is dark and emotional.